Beschrijving van de collection Cornelis Hendrik van Schooneveld
Universiteitsbibliotheek Leiden
Collection Cornelis Hendrik van Schooneveld
1952-2003
Schooneveld, Cornelis Hendrik van (1921-2003)
285 boxes; c.40 m.
Persoonlijk archief van C.H. van Schooneveld (1921-2003), hoogleraar slavistiek. De collectie bevat duizenden dossiers in verband met zijn werk in de jaren 1953-1982 als redacteur van drie wetenschappelijke reeksen van de voormalige Haagse uitgeverij Mouton & Co. Daarnaast bevat de collectie o.m. de beroepsmatige correspondentie die Van Schooneveld heeft gevoerd als hoogleraar Slavische talen aan achtereenvolgens de universiteiten van Leiden, Stanford en Indiana (Bloomington).
Private archive of C.H. van Schooneveld, (1921-2003), professor of Slavic studies. The collection consists of thousands of files concerning his editorial work in 1953-1982 on three scientific series published by the former The Hague publisher Mouton & Co. Additionally, the collection also contains the correspondence written by Van Schooneveld during his position as professor of Slavic Studies at Leiden University, the University of Stanford and the University of Indiana (Bloomington), respectively.
Universiteit Leiden
Cornelis Hendrik van Schooneveld was born on 19 January 1921 in The Hague. In 1938 he started his study in Slavistics at Leiden University, under the supervision of professor N. van Wijk. Van Wijk died in 1941, but not before legating his library to Leiden University Library. In the years 1941-1942 (after Leiden University had been closed down by the German occupiers) Van Schooneveld was employed by the University Library, in order to catalogue Van Wijk’s books. He completed his studies in 1946. A Rockefeller Fellowship enabled him to continue his studies in the United States, at Columbia University, New York. After this appointment Van Schooneveld taught Russian and German at the University of Oklahoma. In 1952 Van Schooneveld was appointed at Leiden University, as professor of Balto-Slavic languages. In 1959 he worked as a visiting professor at Stanford University in California. When this institute offered him a permanent appointment as professor of Slavistics he left Leiden University (July 1960). From 1966 onwards until his retirement in 1986 Van Schooneveld worked as a professor at Indiana University, Bloomington.
In the period 1953-1983 Van Schooneveld also worked on behalf of the publishing house Mouton & Co, The Hague as editor-in-chief of three internationally renowned series in the field of slavistics, linguistics and literary studies: Slavistic printings and reprintings, Janua linguarum, and De proprietatibus litterarum. Van Schooneveld died in 2003 in Vozérier-Amancy, France.
Prof Dr C.H. van Schooneveld (Vozérier-Amancy, France) donated his private archive to Leiden University Library in 1998. In 2007 and 2008 his widow, Mrs. Dorothy van Schooneveld-Abel, donated additional archival materials from his estate.
In the years 1953-1982 Van Schooneveld in his capacity as editor-in-chief supervised the publication of about 800 books in the Mouton series Slavistic printings and reprintings (slavistics), Janua linguarum (linguistics) and De proprietatibus litterarum (literary studies). His archive contains several thousands editorial files, which makes it possible to reconstruct the genesis of almost all books in the mentioned series. Part of these files contain data concerning manuscripts that have been rejected. Another part of the archive contains the correspondence which Van Schooneveld kept in his capacity as professor in Slavistics at the universities of Leiden, Stanford and Indiana, respectively.
The papers (285 boxes in total) have been subdivided in: A. ‘Archives regarding Mouton and related activities’; 165 boxes (inv.nrs. 1-13). – B. ‘Professional correspondence’; 53 boxes (inv.nrs. 14-25). – C. ‘Scholarly notes and manuscripts’; 38 boxes (inv. 26-30). – D. ‘Scholarly documentation’; 19 boxes (inv.nrs. 31-36). – E. ‘Personal papers’; 10 boxes (inv.nrs. 37-39).
The material can be requested in the Catalogue and can be consulted in the Special Collections Reading Room.
The main access to the collection is the inventory by Hinrichs in this collection level description (see below). At present the letters have not been described in the Leiden Catalogue (Letters).
The editorial papers of em. professor Werner Winter, Kiel University, concerning the scientific series Trends in Linguistics (1968-1985) – initially published by Mouton & Co, The Hague, later by Mouton de Gruyter, Berlin – is kept in the Bibliotheca Publica Latina Collection under shelfmark BPL 3526.
Album Scholasticum Academiae Lugduno-Batavae MCMLXXV-MCMLXXXIX. Leiden 1991. p. 149.
Hinrichs, J.P., The C.H. van Schooneveld Collection in Leiden University Library. Editorial correspondence and documents relating to Mouton & Co., The Hague, and other papers in the fields of Slavistics and linguistics. With contributions by A.Th. Bouwman. Leiden 2001. (Codices manuscripti, 31).
Nederlandse basisclassificatie
06.23 = uitgeven, uitgeverij; 18.50 = Slavische talen; 17.01 = algemene taalwetenschap: algemeen; 17.70 = algemene literatuurwetenschap: algemeen
Dutch Basic Classification
06.23 = book production, book distribution; 18.50 = Slavonic languages; 17.01 = linguistics and study of literature: general; 17.70 = study of literature: general
Onderwerpen
Slavistiek; Taalwetenschap; Uitgeverijen
Subjects
Slavonic studies; Linguistics; Publishing companies
Personen
Schooneveld, Cornelis Hendrik van (1921-2003); Ridder, Peter de (1923- )
Persons
Schooneveld, Cornelis Hendrik van (1921-2003); Ridder, Peter de (1923- )
Inventory (Hinrichs 2008)
- Archives regarding Mouton and related activities (inv. nos. 1-13)., A.
  - Mouton editor's correspondence., 1.; Correspondence, in alphabetical order by name, concerning manuscripts that were earmarked for publication in the Mouton series Slavistic printings and reprintings, Janua linguarum and De proprietatibus litterarum.; 97 boxes.; Every manuscript (in some case there is only a plan or an idea) received its own folder. Many authors have more than one folder in this editorial archive. The folders contain letters and documents concerning the manuscripts published by Mouton, as well as manuscripts that were rejected or otherwise not published for whatever reason. The size of the folders varies between a single copy of the letter from Mouton inviting an author to submit the manuscript of his dissertation to Van Schooneveld for consideration, to hundreds of pieces concerning publication in one of the series' Festschrifts. An average folder includes correspondence between Van Schooneveld and the author; a 'manuscript evaluation form' (a Mouton-internal form filled out by Van Schooneveld); letters of the author to Van Schooneveld; the originals and copies of the correspondence between Mouton and Van Schooneveld (either letters or telex messages) concerning a certain manuscript; and copies of the correspondence between Mouton and the authors. NB. See also the mail logs in Inv. No. 38.; The spelling of the Slavic personal names the transcription used in European scholarly libraries, including, where necessary, diacritics, even if it is sometimes different from the spelling as it occurs in Mouton publications or in documents and letters in the Van Schooneveld Collection. For instance, O. Akhmanova is found under Achmanova, V. Setchkarev under Sečkarev, N. Trubetzkoy under Trubeckoj, while M. Součkova is spelled Součková.
    - A
      1. ﻿ Aarts, J. (Computational model for the interpretation of poetry). - 2. Aav, J. (Russian dictionaries: dictionaries and glossaries printed in Russia 1627-1917). - 3. Abbe, D. van (The foundations of language teaching). - 4. Abboud, P.F. (The syntax of Najdi Arabic). - 5. Abdel-Malek, Z.M. (The closed-list classes of colloquial Egyptian Arabic). - 6. Abdel-Massih, E.T. (A course in spoken Tamazight). - 7. Abe, I. (A study of English intonation). - 8. vacant. - 9. Abernathy, R. (Harvard Russia project). - 10. Abou-seida, A.M. (Diglossia in Egyptian Arabic: prolegomena to a Pan-Arabic socio-linguistic study). - 11. Aboul-Fetouh, H.M. (A morphological study of Egyptian colloquial Arabic). - 12. Abraham, S. (Introduction to formal languages). - 13. Abraham, S., and F. Kiefer (A theory of structural semantics). - 14. Abraham, W. (Festschrift for P.A. Verburg). - 15. Abraham, W. (Terminologie zur neueren Linguistik). - 16. Abraham, W. (Terminology of modern linguistics). - 17. Abrahams, R.D. (Collection of articles). - 18. Abrahamson, A.A. (Tutorial bibliography of child language). - 19. Abramowicz, Z. (Homer). - 20. Abramson, A.S. (Status report on speech research). - 21. Achmanova, O.S., and G. Mikaeljan (editors) (The theory of syntax in modern linguistics). - 22. vacant. - 23. Achmanova, O.S. (Bibliography). - 24. Achmanova, O.S. (Dictionary of homonyms). - 25. Achmanova, O.S. (Dictionary of linguistic terminology). - 26. Achmanova, O.S. (Linguostylistics: theory and method). - 27. Achmanova, O.S. (Očerki po obščej i russkoj leksikologii). - 28. Achmanova, O.S. (Phonetics of Russian for English-speaking students). - 29. Achmanova, O.S. (Phonology, morphonology, morphology.). - 30. Achmanova, O.S. (Problems of optimal communication systems). - 31. Achmanova, O.S. (ed.) (Lexicology: theory and method). - 32. Achmanova, O.S. (Slovar’ omonimov russkogo jazyka). - 33. Achutina, T.B. (Translation of: Nejrolingvističeskij analiz dinamičeskoj afazii). - 34. Adams, B.S. (Milton and metaphor: the ‘Artis Logicae’ and the imagery of the shorter English poems). - 35. Adams, C. (English speech and the foreign learner). - 36. Adams, J. (A syntactic approach to Yeats). - 37. Adams, K. (Translation of G.P. de Ridder: From dialect to world language: the evolution of Spanish). - 38. Adams, R.H. (The significance of point of view in Katherine Anne Porter’s ‘Ship of Fools’). - 39. Adamson, R.L. (Phonemic dictionary of English). - 40. Adamus, M. (Genetic typology of languages). - 41. Addison, B.K. (The everlasting was: the past in the works of William Faulkner). - 42. Adenwala, M. (The structural analysis of phonology and morphemics of Gujarati). - 43. Adicks, R.R. Jr. (Structure and meaning in Tennysons’s ‘Idylls of the King’). - 44. Admoni, V.G. (Osnovy teorii grammatiki (translation)). - 45. Adrados, F.R. (Linguistica indoeuropea). - 46. Adrianova, V.P. - 47. Afanas’ev, A. (Russkie narodnye legendy). - 48. Afanasev, A. (Žitie Alekseja čeloveka Božija). - 49. vacant. - 50. Agarie, N. (Effects of verbal contexts on meaning: a study of the connotive meaning of words in isolation and combination). - 51. Agnello, J.G. (A study of intra- and inter-phrasal pauses and their relationship to the rate of speech). - 52. Agnew, G.K. (An approach to ‘Love’s Labour’s Lost’). - 53. Agricola, E. (Semantische Relationen im Text und im System). - 54. Aguas (English composition errors of Tagalog speakers and implications for analytical theory). - 55. Aho, A.V. (Indexed grammars: an extension of context-free grammars). - 56. Aikin, J.P. (Traditional Christian views of history and politics in the dramas of Daniel Caspar von Lohenstein). - 57. Aitzetmüller, R. (Handwörterbuch zu den altkirchenslavischen Texten). - 58. Akagi, T. (The literary development of the Coptic gospels of Thomas). - 58bis. Akan Dictionary. - 59. Akin, J. (ed.) (Language behavior: Festschrift in honor of Elwood Murray). - 60. Akmajian, A. (Collected works). - 61. Akmajian, A., S.M. Steele, and T. Wasow (The category AUX in universal grammar). - 62. Aksakov, K. - 63. Al-Ani, S.H. (Readings in Arabic linguistics). - 64. Al-Ani, S.H. (Arabic phonology). - 65. Al-Kasimi, A.M. - 66. Alekseev, M.P. (Voltaire’s private library in Leningrad). - 67. Alexander, A.E. (The origins of Russian heroic poetry). - 68. Alexander, E. (Matthew Arnold and John Ruskin: classical and romantic in the Victorian age). - 69. Alexander, J. (Analogies among the arts in 18th century British criticism). - 70. Alexander, M.E. (The vital centrality: an essay in phenomenological aesthetics on the human self-image). - 71. Ali, F.A. - 72. Alkire, G.H. - 73. Allen, D.E., and R. Guy (Conversation analysis). - 74. Allen, J. III (Fluid areas of the verb in modern written Russian). - 75. Allen, R.L. (The verb system of present-day American English). - 76. Allen, W.S. (Collected writings). - 77. Allen, W.S. (Sandhi (1962)). - 78. Allison, D.B. (Derrida’s critique of Husserl: The Philosophy of presence). - 79. Allott, R. (The natural origin of languages). - 80. Alquen, R.J. d’ - 81. Altbauer, M. (ed. ) (Sinaitica). - 82. Altman, C. (The shape of narrative). - 83. Altmann, G. (Quantative phonology). - 84. Amante, D. (The structure of irony). - 85. Amse-de Jong, T.H. (The meaning of the finite verb forms in the Codex Suprasliensis). - 86. Ananthanasayana - 87. Andersen, F.I. (Comparative syntax of N.W. Semiti). - 88. Andersen, F.I. (Phrase-Struct. of Classical Heb.). - 89. Andersen, F.I. (The Sentence in Biblical Hebrew). - 90. Andersen, F.I. (Verbal clause in class. Hebrew). - 91. Andersen, F.I. - 92. Anderson, B.F. (The short-term relation of active and passive sentences ). - 93. Anderson, D.C. - 94. Anderson, E.B. - 95. Anderson, I.Z. (The Bible in the theatre of the absurd). - 96. Anderson, J.D. (Development of English-French...). - 97. Anderson, J.M. (Ancient Iberian Languages). - 98. Anderson, J. (An essay concerning aspect). - 99. Anderson, J.H. - 100. Anderson, R.B. (Narrative structures in the prose of Karamzin). - 101. Anderson, R.D. - 102. Anderson, S.R. (West Scandinavian vowel systems). - 103. Anderson, S.R. (On the syntax of ergative languages). - 104. Anderson, T.R. - 105. Andreyev, N.D. - 106. Andronov, M.S. - 107. Angeli, E.S. de - 108. Angyal, A. - 109. Annan, W.R.B. - 110. Ans, A.M. d’ (Le créole français d’Haiti). - 111. Anselmo, P.M. - 112. Anson, J.S. - 113. Antal, L. - 114. Antal, L. (Die Wirklichkeit der Sprache). - 115. Anthila, Raimo - 116. Anthony, E.M. (Towards a theory of lexical meaning). - 117. Anwar, M .S. (Equational sentences in Egyptian colloquial Arabic). - 118. Aoki, H. - 119. Appel, W. - 120. Applegate, J.R. - 121. Apresjan, Ju.D. - 122. Apresjan, Ju.D. (Bibliography). - 123. Apresjan, Ju.D. (Idei i metody...). - 124. Apresjan, Ju.D. (Problems in structural semantics). - 125. Apresjan, Ju.D. (Selected articles). - 126. Apresjan, Ju.D. (Sovietica). - 127. Apter, R. (Creative translation: the influence of Ezra Pound on the translation of poetry). - 128. Arant, P. - 129. Araujo, V. de - 130. Arbeitman, Y. (Translation of writings of Professor Otto Rossler). - 131. Archer, M.S. - 132. Arkwright, T.D. - 133. Armstrong, D., and L. Waugh (ROJ and CHvS morphology study). - 134. Armstrong, D., R. Pope and C.H. van Schooneveld (eds.) (Nicolaas van Wijk: Paterikon). - 135. Arnold, J.B. - 136. Aronson, H.I. (Bulgarian inflectional morphophonology). - 137. Aronson, H.I. (Georgian linguists project). - 138. Aroutunova, B. - 139. Arthur, A.R. - 140. Artinian, R.W. - 141. Arutjunova, N.D. (Sovietica). - 142. Aschenbrenner, Karl, et. al. (Metaphor). - 143. Ascher, G.J. (Die Zauberflöte und die Frau...). - 144. Ashby, W.J. (Prefixed inflection in French, an historical perspective). - 145. Ashida, M.E. - 146. Ashley, J.D. - 147. Ashley, R.P. - 148. Ashmead, J. - 149. Asselt, J. van - 150. Astier, P. - 151. Atai, P. - 152. Atkinson, J.C. (The two forms of subject inversion in Modern French). - 153. Atkinson, J.E. (Aspects of intonation in speech; implications from an experimental study of...). - 154. Aubrey, A. (The organization and assumptions of the medieval Artes Poetr.). - 155. Augerot, J.E. - 156. Augerot, J. E. (Romanian grammar pamphlets). - 157. Augst, B.T. - 158. August, E.R. - 159. Austin, W. (Selected writings). - 160. Austin, W.M. (ed.) (Dostert Festschrift). - 161. Avakian, H. (Isolation of the language area: neurolinguistic implications). - 162. Avanesov, R.I. - 163. Avram, A. (Études de phonologie générale). - 164. Awwad, M. (Palestinian colloquial Arabic). - 165. Awwal, M.(Prose Works...). - 166. Aylward, K.J. - 167. Azadovskij, A., and J. Stokolov - 168. Azevedo, M.M. (On passive sentences in English and Portuguese).
    - B
      169. Baar, A.H. van den - 170. Babby, L. - 171. Babcock, Sandra Schartff - 172. Babinski, H.F. - 173. Babula, W. - 174. Bach, E. - 175. Bach, E. (Collection of articles). - 176. Bachinger, K. (Edgar Allan Poe’s Byronographies). - 177. Bachtin, M.M. - 178. Bachtin, M.M. (Problemy poètiki Dostoevskogo). - 179. Bachtin, M.M. (Sovietica). - 180. Bacon, R.L. (Literary theory: a pedagogy). - 181. Badalić, J. - 182. Baer, J.T. - 183. Baetens Beardsmore, H. - 184. Baeyens, M. (Generative semantics). - 185. Bagg, R.E. - 186. Bahnick, K. - 187. Bailey, J. - 188. Bailey, R.W. (Inactive). - 189. Baily, B.L. - 190. Baines, J. - 191. Bakalla, M.H. - 192. Baker, C.F. (The rags and bones of fictive worlds). - 193. Baker, J.L. (Grammar with structured vocabulary). - 194. Baker, N.E. (The concept of concept). - 195. Baker, W.E. - 196. Balázs, J. - 197. Bald, W.D. - 198. Bald, W.D. (Theory and evidence in linguistics...). - 199. Baldi, P. - 200. Baldwin, J.R. (Intonation of modern coll. Rus.). - 201. Balk, F. - 202. Ball, D.L. - 203. Ball, R.J. (The structure of Tibullus’s elegies). - 204. Baltaxe, C. (Trubeckoj volume). - 205. Baltzell, J.L. - 206. Banta, A.E. - 207. Bantas, A. - 208. Bar-Adon, A. - 209. Bar Adon, A. - 210. Bar-Hillel, M.M. - 211. Bar-Hillel, Y. - 212. Barasch, F.K. - 213. Bárbara, L., and M. Kato (Portuguese collection). - 214. Barik, H.C. - 215. Barik, H.C. - 216. Barkai, M. (Aphasic evidence for underlying representation). - 217. Barkman, L.B. - 218. Barnes, N.S. - 219. Barnett, A.W. - 220. Baron, D.E. (Case grammar and diachronic English syntax). - 221. Baron, D.E. (Case grammar & diachronic English syntax). - 222. Baron, N. (Phylogenetic reflections of ontogenetic process). - 223. Barooshian, V.D. (Brik and Mayakovsky). - 224. Barooshian, V.D. (Russian cubo-futurism 1910-1930: a study in avant-gardism). - 225. Barr, J. - 226. Barrack, C.M. - 227. Barrada, M. (Stylistic inquiry). - 228. Barratt, G.R. (An exegis of the verse of E.A. Baratynskij in the context of the movements of his time). - 229. Barratt, G.R. (M.S. Lunin: the catholic Decembrist). - 230. Barratt, G.R. (Selected letters of Evgenij Baratynskij). - 231. Barrett, A.W. (Who is Jacob? The Quest for identity in the writing of Virginia Woolf.). - 232. Barrett, A.G. - 233. Barrett, R.P. - 234. Barrutia, R. - 235. Barsov, N.P. (Newman, ed.). - 236. Barsov, N.P. (Slovo o polku Igoreve I-III). - 237. Barsov, T. (Konstantinopol’skij patriarch i ego vlast’ nad russkoju cerkoviju). - 238. Barthel, J.W. - 239. Barthes, R. - 240. Bartlett, B.E. (The theory & methodology of Beauzée’s ‘Grammaire générale’). - 241. Bartley, R.H. - 242. Barton, C. - 243. Bascom, B.W., Jr. - 244. Bates, R.R. - 245. Battersby, J.L. Jr. - 246. Battle, J.H. - 247. Baxter, C.L. Jr. - 248. Bayerle, G. (Ottoman tributes in Hungary). - 249. Beard, R.E. - 250. Beard, R.E. 251. Beards, R.D. - 251bis. Beauchamp, W. (The style of Nerval’s ‘Aurelia’). - 252. Becker, A.L. - 253. Beckers, H., and H. Schwarz (Jost Trier memorial volume). - 254. Bee, D.L. - 255. Beebe - 256. Beekes, R.S.P. - 257. Beekey, L.E. - 258. vacant. - 259. Belaval, D.D. de - 260. Belchita, A. (Transformational morphophonemics of Modern Romanian). - 261. Beleckij, A.A. (Leksikologija i teorija jazykoznanija). - 262. Belgardt, R. - 263. Belinkov, A. - 264. Belknap, R.L. - 265. Bell, A. (The language of radio news in Auckland: a socio-linguistic study of style, audience and subediting variation for pub). - 266. Bell, R.T. - 267. Bellert, I. - 268. Bellugi-Klima, U. - 269. Belson, and J. Jay - 270. Beltramo, A.F. - 271. Ben-Zvi, L. (The devaluation of language in avant-garde drama). - 272. Bender, L.M. (The Afroasiatic languages). - 273. Bendor-Samuel, D. - 274. Benedict, H.E. (Learning to understand: the structure of early language comprehension). - 275. Benediktsson, H. - 276. Benko, L., and S. Imre (The Hungarian language). - 277. Bennett, J. - 278. Benoit, R.P. - 279. Benouis, M. (Le dialogue philosophique dans la litterature française du seizième siecle). - 280. Benson, L.D. - 281. Bentley, C.A. - 282. Berberova, N.N. - 283. Bereczki, G., and L. Vikár (Chuvash folksongs). - 284. Beresford, M. - 285. Berezin, F.M. - 286. Bergen, J.J. (Set theory applied to Spanish entity labels). - 287. Berghe, C. van den - 288. Berghe, C. van den (La pensée de Saint-Exupérie). - 289. Berkeley, D.S. - 290. Berkoben, L.D. - 291. Berlin, B. - 292. Berman, M. - 293. Bernaut, E. - 294. Berry, A.F. (Rabelais: homo logos). - 295. Berry-Rogghe, G. - 296. Berry, T.E. - 297. Berryman, C.B. - 298. Berstman, C.A. (Bernard Shaw’s comic perspective: a view of self and reality ). - 299. Bertman, S.S. - 300. Bettetini, G. - 301. Betz, P.F. - 302. Bever, T.G. - 303. Bever, T.G., and W. Weksel (Structure; Psychology of language). - 304. Bever, T.G., and J.J. Katz (The fall and rise of empiricism, or, the truth about generative semantics). - 305. Bhatia, R.G. - 306. Bhatia, T. (Negation in South Asian languages). - 307. Biart, J. (Turkic philology). - 308. Bidu-Vranceanu, A. (Recherche de méthode en sémantique). - 309. Bidwell, C.E. (Outline of Czech morphology). - 310. Bidwell, C.E. (I J S L P). - 311. Bierwisch, M. (Intonation in German). - 312. Bierwisch, M. (Collection of crticles). - 313. Bierwisch, M. (Modern linguistics). - 314. Bierwisch, M. (Strukturalismus). - 315. Bierwisch, M., and K.E. Heidolph (eds.) (Progress in linguistics). - 316. Bihari, J. (Slavisches Erbe in einer germanischen...). - 317. Bilokur, B. - 318. Binh, D.T. - 319. Binkert, P.J. - 320. Birgegàrd, U. (Sparwenfeldt dictionary). - 321. Birke, J. W. - 322. Birkeland, H. - 323. Birkenmayer, S.S. - 324. Birn, R.M.I. - 325. Birnbaum, H. (Balkan conf.). - 326. Birnbaum, H. (Common Slavic). - 327. Birnbaum, H. (Slavic writing...). - 328. Birnbaum, H. (New essays in Early Slavic civilization). - 329. Birnbaum, H. (Problems of typological and genetic linguistics viewed in generative framework.). - 330. Bishop (The Language of Poetry). - 331. Black, J.W. - 332. Blache, S. - 333. Black, J. L. (Karamzin symposium). - 334. Black, J.L. - 335. Black, J.W. - 336. Black, J.W., et al. (A select utilization of…). - 337. Bladon, R.A.W. - 338. Blair, R. W. - 339. Blake, R.E. - 340. Blanchard, E.S. - 341. Blane, A. (ed.) (Florovsky Festschrift). - 342. Blank, P.E. Jr. - 343. Blansitt, E.L. Jr. - 344. Blau, J. (The emergence and linguistic background of Judaeo-Arabic: a study of origins of Middle Arabic). - 345. Blaylock, W.C. - 346. Blekastad, M. - 347. Blesser, B.A. (Perception of spectrally rotated speech). - 348. Blitch, A. - 349. Block, D. (The structure of relative clauses). - 350. Blodgett, H. - 351. Blok, D.P. (ed.) (8th International Congress of Onomastic Sciences). - 352. Bloom, L. (Collection of articles). - 353. Bloom, L. (One word at a time). - 354. Bloom, V. (Semantic empiricism: toward a critical perspective for communication inquiry). - 355. Blum, J.M. - 356. Blume, B. (Festschrift). - 357. Blumenthal, A.L. - 358. Blumstein, S. - 359. Bodoh, J.J. - 360. Boecker, E. - 361. Bogdanov, A.N., and L.G. Judkerič (Metodika literaturovedčeskogo analiza). - 362. Bogojavlensky, M. - 363. Boguslawski, A. (Problems of the thematic-rhematic structures of sentences). - 364. Bohnert, H.G. - 365. Bolinger, D.L. - 366. Bolinger, D.L. (Form-content panel, San Francisco, speeches). - 367. Bolinger, D.L. (MLA Convention - form-content papers). - 368. Bolinger, D.L. - 369. Bolinger, D.L. (Collected articles on English grammar). - 370. Bolinger, D.L. (Degree words). - 371. Bolinger, D.L. (That’s that). - 372. Bondarko, A.V. (Semantičeskie funkcii v grammatike). - 373. Bonnell, P.H. (The technical devices of Aleksandr Ivanovič Kuprin). - 374. Boon, J.P. - 375. Boorse, C. (Naturalism without indeterminacy). - 376. Boos, F. - 377. Borg, A. - 378. Borkowski, C.G. - 379. Bornhauser, F.W. - 380. Borton, S. (Six modes of sensibility). - 381. Borzakovskij, V.S. - 382. Bosley, R. - 383. Bot Ba Njock, and H. Marcel (Dialect atlas of Cameroun). - 384. Botha, R.P. - 385. Botha, R.P. - 386. Botha, R.P. (Collection of articles). - 387. Botha, R.P. (Methodological aspects of transformational generative phonology). - 388. Botha, R.P. (The conduct of linguistic inquiry: a systematic introduction to the methodology of of generative grammar). - 389. Botha, R.P. (The methodological status of grammatical argumentation). - 390. Botha, R., and W.K. Winckler (Justification of linguistic hypotheses). - 391. Botheroyd, P.F. - 392. Boudreault, M., and F. Möhren (Proceedings of the XII Inter. Congress). - 393. Boulger, J.D. (The Calvinistic temper in English poetry). - 394. Bouma, L. - 395. Bourquin, G. (Piers Plowman: études sur la genèse littéraire des trois versions). - 396. Bousek, K. - 397. Bowit (Institute of Modern Russian Culture). - 398. Bowling, A. - 399. Boyd, J. - 400. Boyer, R. E. (English declarations). - 401. Bradley, A.G. (Pastoral in the novels of George Eliot). - 402. Brady, P. (Structuralist perspectives in fiction criticism: essays on...). - 403. Brainerd, B. (Statistics language and style). - 404. Braithwaite, W.R. - 405. Brannen, N.S. - 406. Bras, M.T. - 407. Braude, S. - 408. Braun, J.T. - 409. Bray, R.G.A. de - 410. Brecht, R. (Deixis hypostasis in Russian). - 411. Brekle, H.E., and H. Aarsleff (17th & 18th c. in Linguistics). - 412. Brekle, H.E. (Semantik). - 413. Brekle, H.E., and L.Lipka (eds.) (Marchand Festschrift). - 414. Brenckle, J. - 415. Brend, R.M. - 416. Brend, R.M. - 417. Brend, R.M. (ed.) (Festschrift Kenneth L. Pike). - 418. Brenner, G. - 419. Breschinsky, Z.A. - 420. Bresnan, J. - 421. vacant. - 422. Breymayer, R. (ed.) (Selected works of Propp). - 423. Brière, E.J. - 424. Bright, W. - 425. Bright, W. (Collection of articles). - 426. Brink, D.T. (Problems in phonological theory). - 427. Brinke, J.S. ten - 428. Britton, Celia (Novels of Nathalie Sarraute). - 429. Brkić, J. - 430. Brock, P. - 431. Brock, P. (Nationalism, populism; Romantic socialism in partitioned Poland ). - 432. Brockett, O.G. (Poetry as instrument). - 433. Brockett, O.G. (ed.) (Heffner Festschrift). - 434. Brockhaus, K. - 435. Brodskij, N.L., et al. (eds.) (Literaturnye manifesty ). - 436. Brodsky, S.L. - 437. Brody, E.C. - 438. Bronowski, J. (Language and biology). - 439. vacant. - 440. Brooks, M.Z. (Polish reference grammar). - 441. Brophy, James - 442. Bross, I.D.J. - 443. Brown, A.K. (The Epinal glossary). - 444. Brown, C.H. (An ordinary language approach to transformational grammar and to formal semantic analysis of Huastec terminological systems ). - 445. Brown, E. J. (Conference on literature and politics in the Soviet Union, Stanford Univ.). - 446. Brown, E.C. - 447. Brown, R.G. - 448. Brown, R.L. - 449. Brown, R.W. - 450. Brown, S.L. - 451. Brown, W.H. Jr. - 452. Browning, B.W. (Artifice visible: literary mannerism in the dramas of Daniel Casper von Lohenstein). - 453. Bruckner, J. - 454. Bruffee, K.A. - 455. Bruhn, G.B. - 456. Brumble, D. III. (Translation Bredero Spanish Brabanter). - 457. Brumlik, A.J. (The uses of fiction in Chrétien de Troyes). - 458. Brunner, C.J. (Syntax of Western Middle Iranian). - 459. Bruns, G.L. - 460. Brutian, G.A. - 461. Bruzina, R.C. - 462. Bryan, G.A. - 463. Brylowski, W.M. - 464. Brzozowski, S. - 465. Buch, Tamara - 466. Buchwald, E. - 467. Bucsela, John - 468. Budagov, R.A. - 469. Buehler, G.H. - 470. Buehler, P.G. (Genesis and exodus). - 471. Bueno, A.A. (The meaning of meaning and the meaning of poetry). - 472. Buffington, R.R. - 473. Buhler, C. (Ausdruckstheorie). - 474. Buhler, K. - 475. Bukatevič, N.I. (Očerki po sravnitel’noj grammatike vostočnoslavjanskich jazykov). - 476. vacant. - 477. Bulhof, F. (Word frequency list on Thomas Mann). - 478. Bulič, S.K. - 479. Bull, V. (The problem of Evil ). - 480. Bullard, M. (on revenge in Beowulf ). - 481. Bulwa, L. (The intervening narrator: a study of Henry de Montherlant’s ‘Jeunes Filles’ series). - 482. Bulygina, T.V. - 483. Bung, K. - 484. Bung, K. (Theory of programmed language instruct